Thea Olivia Yusuf

Software/Data Engineer

+46 73 3953 018 ☐
theaolivia.mail@gmail.com ☑
https://teaolivia.github.io/

https://github.com/teaolivia 🕠

https://www.linkedin.com/in/theaolivia/

I am a data/software engineer from Indonesia but currently based in Stockholm, Sweden. Currently I am involved in migrating a monolith application of size in petabytes to microservices with Unity Technologies since late Summer 2022. Before I worked on data pipeline transformation with Klarna for 2 years and 6 months. Back then I have experience on various backend and even frontend projects which build my software design fundamentals.

Experience

Unity Technologies

August 2022 -

- Software Engineer
- Engage both 220 external and 7000 internal customer by built Unity's IAM solution with SCIM/OIDC policy written in Go and integrated with Okta's Autho
- Reduce company cost by 50% by designing and migrating from monolith to micro service application written in Go utilising
 MongoDB including their Atlas service, deployed with Docker container inside Kubernetes and run on Google Cloud
 Platform.
- · Improved troubleshooting and on-call experience by maintaining and using Grafana dashboard using Prometheus metrics
- Reduce the vulnerabilities of project by participating in threat modelling session with the team and implemented REST security recommendations from OWASP, we were using OWASP ZAP for this one.

Klarna

Data Engineer

June 2020 - July 2022

- Speeded up decisions with serve 4 variables in just 1 week by maintain and improve serving layer of Klarna data
 processing powerhouse written mainly in Java, consisted of AWS Lambda and DynamoDB ingestion, Kafka
 realtime ingestion and RabbitMQ that run upon AWS EC2 which is containered by Docker
- Shortened pipeline processing time from 24 to 12 hours by decommissioned an old realtime database system and create
 new model result with PosgreSQL that executed with Airflow which send to AWS Redshift, carefully deployed with
 Jenkins and some Ansible script with some Python3 automation scripts
- Increased stakeholder engagement by 30% and less onboarding time using ReactJS and some GraphQL
- Increased team productivity and data correctness by 20% by participate in on-call rotations to ensure quality of the
 pipeline service through monitoring with Splunk, QlikSense and DataDog
- Increased speed of market acquisition by 15% by doing ETLjob

Software Engineer

January 2020 - June 2020

- Improved candidate acquisition amount from 10 to 20% of daily batch by designed and built an internal extension of Lever, a popular HR management software which is written in Python3 with Flask framework containered with Docker
- Speeded up recruiters accountability from 1 month follow-up time gap to the slowest is 2 weeks by did ETL job of Lever external data and clean up internal data that is the result of the ETL job and stored in **AWS RDS**

Freelance Software Developer

January 2018 - December 2019

- · Acted as a software consultant for small to medium businesses
- Designed and implemented RESTful API using Flask which is written in Python server for a project which develop a coupon sharing social media web application, also orchestrate to deploy on cloud service which was AWS EC2

Projects

2023 DuckStream, https://github.com/teaolivia/DuckStream

A React-based WebOS TV app that can play videos that can be served in separate server. Currently ongoing.

2019 viral.in, https://github.com/teaolivia/viral.in and https://github.com/teaolivia/viralin-client

One of freelancing project. An app which combined discount coupon and social media. Designed and implemented RESTful API with Flask and ReactJS for frontend. Containered with Docker which ran upon AWS stack.

Accomplishment

2021 Participant in Google Hash Code 2021

2017 Participant in ACM-ICPC 2017 Regional Contest in Southeast Asia region

2016 Selected as one of the finalists team in Facebook Indonesia Developer Challenge

Education

Bandung Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

September 2011 - April 2018

Thesis Malware Detection in Application Layer with Machine Learning Methods

Courseworks Algorithm and Data Structures, Object-Oriented Programming, Distributed and Parallel Systems, Databases,

Machine Learning